You're working too hard.
你会不会太拼了？
What do you think you're doing?
你在想什么啊？
Aren't you worried about Old Man?
难道你不担心大叔吗？
You even agreed to get transferred to another division.
而且还同意调去其他部队
I want to be stronger.
因为我想变强
You can become stronger here.
在这里也可以吧？
That's how we've done it until now, right?
我们不就是在这里变强的吗？
You're right. I think we can get stronger if we stay.
的确，我觉得就算在这里也能变强
But I want to get stronger as quickly as possible.
但是，我想要尽快变强
I don't want to be protected.
我不想总是被保护
Next time, I want to be the one to protect Senpai.
下次，要由我来保护前辈
I believe it.
我相信他
When that time comes, I don't want to have any regrets because of my weakness.
到那时候，我不想 再因为我的弱小而后悔
Sure, me too, but…
我也是啊，可是…
Shit, I'll do it too, then! I can't be losing to you!
我也会变强的，可恶！ 怎么能输给你这家伙呢？
It's rowdy in here.
干嘛？怎么这么吵？
Senpai…
前辈…
Today is when they decide Hibino's punishment.
今天要决定日比野的处分
-So, we were all a bit restless. -You guys too, right?
-一想到就静不下来 -你们也是一样吧？
It'll be okay!
没问题的
We wrote the petition with everyone's help.
大家都一起写请愿书了
Captain Ashiro got summoned to Headquarters, too.
亚白队长也被叫去本部基地了
-Captain did? -Yes.
-队长吗？ -对
I'm sure she was summoned to receive good news.
一定是有好消息才叫她去的
This is Mina Ashiro. I am here by order of my superiors.
亚白米娜，奉命前来报到
Director General Shinomiya is assessing Kaiju No. 8 right now.
四之宫长官正在评估怪兽8号
-Please wait there until it is complete. -Roger.
-结束前请在那里稍等 -了解
You are an observer. You have not been provided a seat.
你是观察员，所以没有你的座位
Stop it! You're a human, Kafka Hibino!
快住手！ 你是人类吧，日比野卡夫卡！
He's fast! But these are just thoughtless attacks of an animal. He's defenseless.
速度很快，但不过是野兽般的攻击 没有考虑攻击时的破绽
A self-destructive attack, based on the premise that he'll regenerate.
靠着再生能力的自残攻击吗？
If I think in human terms, he'd get the better of me.
若用人类的常识思考，会吃大亏的
Stop it!
住手！
Without No. 2's armor, I would've died right there.
要是没有2号的护盾 我恐怕已经死了
Squadron-Style Combat Technique Number 2…
队式格斗术2式…
Force Blast!
爆破！
Expanding the field of damage using a sonic boom.
运用音爆扩大打击范围
This is an attack method that No. 2 used often.
这是2号常用的攻击方式
His core is gone?
核心不见了？
He used his flesh as bait to regenerate from his core?
他用肉体当诱饵，从核心再生…
This guy's fighting method is crazy!
这战斗方式太乱来了
My body won't last this way!
我的身体会撑不住的
No way! That's the hardest shelter we have!
不会吧？这可是最硬的收容所啊！
He only broke through the second layer.
他只打破了前两层
Theoretically, it can withstand a Fortitude 10 attack!
理论上这里 可以承受怪兽规模10的攻击
Some damage is to be expected.
有点损失是在所难免
After all, this is a fight
毕竟这可是跨越时空
between two Identified Kaiju reaching across time.
两只识别怪兽 2号和8号的激烈战斗啊
Amazing.
好厉害
He's fighting at an Identified Kaiju level all on his own!
竟然一个人就和 识别怪兽级打得不相上下
But this is strange.
但真奇怪啊
If he meant to kill No. 8, he should have finished him off
如果要杀掉，就应该趁人型状态时
in the first attack, when he was in his human form.
在第一击就痛下杀手
But Isao looks like
但是功他却…
he's trying to push No. 8 past his limit.
却像是在测试8号的能耐
What is he planning?
不知道他有什么打算？
Could it be…
难道爸爸…
Dad's trying to give Kafka Hibino the chance to live?
他打算给 日比野卡夫卡活下来的机会？
I joined
我…
the Defense Force to save people.
是为了救人才加入防卫队
But it was me that got saved by Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡却救了我
But he's…
但是，那家伙…
You shouldn't judge anyone based on their background or what they say.
评断一个人的标准 不是出身，也不是他说的话
You should judge them based on what they do.
而是要根据他做的事情来判断
That's what I think.
我是这么想的
Yeah. You're exactly right.
嗯，你说的没错
DAD
（父亲）
The only truth is action, huh?
行动才是真理吗？
No!
不妙！
No. 8's strength is starting to surpass Isao's predictions.
8号的强度开始超出功的预想了
This is bad. I have to stop this guy.
糟糕，再不阻止这家伙的话…
Shit! Stop it!
可恶，快住手！
I have to do something or Deputy General will…
再这样下去，长官会…
Don't mess with me!
开什么玩笑？
Like I'd let you kill Kikoru's father while she's watching!
怎么能在琪歌露面前杀死她的父亲？
If I ever find out that you're a danger to humans,
如果我知道你是有害人类的怪兽
I'll kill you myself.
我就会杀了你
Even then…
我…
Even then, I want to…
我要把那家伙…
I want to believe in him!
即使如此，我还是想相信他！
Don't be losing to some kaiju, stupid Kafka!
不准输给那种怪兽，笨蛋卡夫卡！
I… I…
我…
APPLICATION RESULTS
（选拔结果通知）
I'm always like this.
我每次都这样
I'm always losing where it's most important.
每次都在重要的时刻搞砸一切
Damn it.
可恶…
I expected more from him, but this is where it ends.
我本来还有所期待，看来到此为止了
I'll always…
我会…
I'll always wait for you.
我会一直等你的
I'm…
我…
I'm not Kaiju No. 8.
我不是怪兽8号
I'm Kafka Hibino.
我是日比野卡夫卡
Drop the weapon,
把武器收起来
Narumi.
鸣海
You never sent the signal for backup.
你一直没有发送支援的信号
I thought you planned on dying.
我还以为你打算送死呢
Don't be dumb.
胡说八道
Though I do admit, things didn't go according to my predictions.
不过我承认，他超出我的预期
Medical team, contain No. 8 right away.
医疗班，立刻将8号收容
His core may be damaged.
他的核心可能有损伤
So, what do you plan
所以，这家伙…
on doing with him?
你打算怎么处理？
The assessment by General Deputy Shinomiya is now complete.
四之宫长官的评估已经结束
Finally, we want to ask you your impressions of him on the field,
最后，我们想听听 现场负责人对他的看法
-Captain Mina Ashiro. -Yes, sir.
-亚白队长 -是
You've been watching Kafka Hibino since he tested to join the force.
你在入队测验之后 就持续关注日比野卡夫卡
According to these documents, you knew him before then.
根据调查报告，你们之前就互相认识
Yes.
是，不过
However, my personal relationship has not influenced my decision on his admission.
从入队测验开始，我就从未手下留情
According to records, she rejected Kafka Hibino's application.
根据记录，她淘汰了日比野卡夫卡
He got accepted as a cadet due to the support of Vice-Captain Hoshina.
成为候补队员是保科副队长的建议
Let me say this before we start. Our decision is already made.
话先说在前头 我们基本上已经得出结论
Your report is just a formality for the records.
你的报告不过是一部分程序
Therefore, your statements will not influence
也就是说，你的发言并不会影响
our decision about Kaiju No. 8.
针对怪兽8号的处置
We don't want you to feel responsible
若你觉得要对这次的处分结果负责
for our final decision.
-那并不是我们的本意 -是
Go on.
继续吧
I do not know whether Kafka Hibino is a man or kaiju.
日比野卡夫卡是人类还是怪兽
That is up to the experts to judge.
只能交给专家去解决
So, today, I will discuss Kafka Hibino's actions as an officer.
因此，我想谈谈 日比野卡夫卡作为队员的表现
At the Sagamihara Neutralization Plan, Officer Kafka Hibino
日比野卡夫卡队员 在相模原讨伐作战时
discovered the reproduction organs of the yoju and contributed greatly.
发现了余兽的增殖器官 为防卫队做出贡献
He continued to work diligently after that and saved his colleagues many times.
之后也继续诚实勤奋地工作 数次拯救了伙伴
His greatest accomplishment against No. 10. He destroyed the yoju explosives
特别是与10号的战斗中 他破坏了余兽炸弹
and saved Division Three from possible complete destruction.
让第3部队免于遭到全灭的危机
How is this relevant?
所以那又怎么样？
That accomplishment was possible because he used his kaiju powers.
这些功劳 都是使用怪兽力量的结果吧？
His immense success despite being a mere rookie officer further proves
他只是个新队员 这些表现不就恰好证明
he is a kaiiju.
他是个怪兽？
Yes. You're exactly right.
是，你说的没错
His Unleashed Combat Power when he joined was at 0%.
加入防卫队时，他的解放战力是0%
When he joined the Force, he squeezed in as a cadet.
入队测验也是勉强候补合格
He's been rejected from the Defense Force 12 times in a row.
之前的防卫队测验 还连续12次不及格
His age, too. He's the oldest amongst the rookies.
在年龄方面，也是新队员中最年长的
So, he committed fraud to join the Force using his kaiju powers!
所以说他是用怪兽的力量作弊吧！
Even so, he didn't give up.
不过，他并没有放弃
No matter how many times he got rejected or if his Combat Power was zero
即使他好几次测验没过 解放战力是零
or if his body turned into a kaiju,
即使他的身体变成怪兽
he never stopped saving people.
他也从来没有放弃救助他人
As far as I know, Kafka Hibino
我所认识的日比野卡夫卡
is the most persistent, dedicated,
比谁都更有毅力、更牺牲
and…
而且…
Meeko!
咪子…
…the most humanistic person I know.
…也比谁都更像人类
How do we judge whether Kafka Hibino is an officer that can be trusted?
判断他是不是 值得信赖的队员的因素是什么？
We judge him by his heart. That's what I believe.
我相信是从内心来判断
We are not asking for your opinion here!
我们不是在征求你的意见
Don't cover for your subordinates.
别再为你的部下辩护了
His heart, you say? We can't rely on such an unreliable thing!
怎么可能相信内心这种模糊的东西？
Good work, Captain Ashiro.
辛苦了，亚白队长
Go back to your post.
请回岗位吧
We've now listened to input from the field.
现场的意见也听过了
Now, no one will consider our decision too hasty.
这样就不会有人说 我们是仓促判断了吧？
We're prepared to deliver any kind of punishment.
已经准备好进行处分了
Deputy General, your decision?
长官，请下决定
No. 8 will be…
8号…
I was so frustrated
好不甘心
at how little I could do.
自己什么都做不到
I thought I'd never forgive kaiju
我绝不会原谅
for making Mina cry this much.
害米娜哭成这样的怪兽
So if I turned into a kaiju, both body and mind,
所以，就算自己的身心都变成怪兽
I wanted to die as a human.
我也想作为人类死去
I'm…
我还…
alive?
活着？
So, you're awake.
你醒了啊
Deputy General Shinomiya!
四之宫长官！
Don't look so guarded. I don't mean to do you any harm.
不用这么警戒，我没有要加害你
I'm so glad.
太好了
If anything
要是…
happened to you, sir,
长官有什么万一
I couldn't look Kikoru in the eyes.
我就没脸见琪歌露了
If I'm alive, does this mean I've been accepted as a human
既然我还活着 就表示防卫队认同我是人类
and as a Defense Force officer?
认同我是防卫队员吗？
If the thing inside your chest
如果你胸前的东西
was the weak heart of a human,
是脆弱的人类心脏的话
you would most likely be dead.
你恐怕早就死了
I'll tell you what our decision is.
告诉你会议的结论吧
You are a kaiju.
你是只怪兽
But it's yet undecided whether you are our enemy or not.
不过，是不是敌人，还有待观察
Right now, most are against keeping you alive.
现在，几乎所有人都反对饶你一命
Kaiju No. 8
怪兽8号
will not be turned into a weapon. Instead, he will fight for us.
目前将不会制成兵器，而是作为战力
I object! To keep a kaiju alive and use him as a soldier?
我反对，怎么能运用活生生的怪兽？
-It's dangerous. -No one has done it before!
-太危险了 -也没有前例可循
I'm not Kaiju No. 8.
我不是怪兽8号
I'm Kafka Hibino.
我是日比野卡夫卡
My assessment was that he can be managed.
我判断他能控制怪兽的能力
He has been working on missions with Third Division for a few months now.
实际上，他也和第3部队 共同执行过数个月的任务
We do not know whether his immense power could be transferred into a weapon.
就算将他做成兵器 也没办法保证发挥同等的力量
With daikaiju appearing in swarms,
在大怪兽频繁出现的现在
we must take full advantage of our fighting capacity.
应该要用最有效率的方式来运用战力
-But there is no precedent for this. -Precedent?
-但是没有前例啊 -前例？
Things like that are minuscule compared to the defense of our nation.
跟我国的防卫相比，根本微不足道
Have you forgotten
我们绝不能忘记
the swarm disaster ten years ago, with No. 6 at the center?
十年前以6号为中心的群发性灾害
We lost over 200 officers and three captains in that fight.
当时有两百名以上的队员 和三名队长殉职
Your wife, too.
也包含你的妻子
When the number of kaiju that appears surpasses our predicted number,
如果接连出现超乎预期数量的怪兽
countries can perish easily.
这个国家可能会轻易毁灭
If we use No. 8's unprecedented power to our advantage,
要是能善用那家伙空前的力量
he could be our hope.
就能成为我们的希望
-Even so, we… -They're against it.
-就算那样，我们也… -反对
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
He called my name!
他叫了我的名字
To survive, you must show us how useful you can be to us.
想活下去的话，就证明你的用处
They're barely
意思是…
letting me live so that I can be their weapon.
让我活着只是为了当作兵器吗？
Even so,
就算是现在
I think of myself as a Defense Force officer.
我也认为自己是防卫队员
I'll make them accept me
我一定会让你们认同我是防卫队员
MINA ASHIRO KAFKA HIBINO'S PUNISHMENT IS PUT ON HOLD
（亚白米娜： 日比野卡夫卡，暂不处分）
Even so,
不过…
we can't just be celebrating.
不能只是高兴
Next time, I have to be stronger, too.
下次我必须变得更强才行
Otherwise, I can't stop him when the time comes.
否则就无法在紧要关头阻止他
Hey.
这是…
Did the SDF have anything to do with this?
自卫队出手了吗？
No, they didn't.
不，不是
That means
那…这是…
Kafka Hibino won this himself.
日比野卡夫卡赢得了胜利
-Yes. -Yeah, he did it!
-太… -太好啦！
Old Man did it! I knew it. It was fated to be this way!
太好啦，大叔，真的是神明保佑啊！
Hell, yeah!
太好啦！
I'm so glad Hibino-san will be okay!
日比野，太好了
It'll get chaotic in here again.
又要变得热闹了
Hey, Reno. Old Man will be safe!
喂，雷诺，大叔平安无事了
I knew it already.
我早就知道了
I told you that Senpai will be back for sure.
我说过吧？前辈一定会回来的
I'll become
我会比以前
stronger than ever before and wait for you, Senpai.
比现在变得更强等着你的，前辈
I'm glad Hibino-san will be okay.
太好了呢，日比野
But now is where the real challenge begins.
接下来才是挑战啊
If it gets out that there is a kaiju inside the Defense Force…
防卫队里有怪兽这件事 要是传出去的话…
That will be kept confidential.
那个，如果是极机密地运用…
Things like this get out eventually.
总有一天会曝光的
I'm sure the higher-ups know that.
上面的人也有觉悟了吧
In that case…
这样的话…
Kafka Hibino has to prove his worth in a way that everyone would accept him.
日比野卡夫卡必须做出 所有人都能接受的结果
I told you, the real challenge is just beginning.
接下来，更大的挑战才要开始啊
Hey. We're not done here. Wake up!
喂，我话还没说完，起来
Wait for me,
等着我吧
Mina.
米娜
What? You lost?
咦，你输了哦？
You only played for seven minutes? That's so fast!
比赛时间七分钟，好快啊！
It's not my fault!
怪我哦？
This Number 9 guy appeared out of nowhere last week and immediately beat everyone!
这个叫9号的家伙上周才出现 却一下就成为顶尖玩家
TOTAL RANKING 1. NUMBER 9
（总排名第一名：9号）
It's that easy, huh?
就这样吧
I understand the basic intellect level of humans now.
我大概了解人类的智慧程度了
For each individual, it's not that high.
个别的程度并没有太大差异
The accumulation of knowledge across generations, that's their real strength.
跨越世代累积智慧 才是他们真正的武器
How's it going over there?
那边如何了？
I've learned the general structure of the base now.
已经大致掌握基地的构造了
Now, we can move onto the next step of our plan.
那么，我们的作战 也进行到下一阶段吧
I see. In that case…
是啊，这样一来
Let's return the kaiju power that has fallen into human hands
该让落入人类手中的怪兽之力
back to the hands of a kaiju, where it belongs.
重新回到怪兽手中了
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰